<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: HTML | Ardent Developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://ardentdeveloper.com/blog/categories/html/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ardentdeveloper.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-20T06:22:47+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://ardentdeveloper.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rony Varghese]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tympanus Codrops - Useful resources and inspiration for creative minds.]]></title>
    <link href="http://ardentdeveloper.com/blog/2013/08/12/tympanus-codrops-useful-resources-and-inspiration-for-creative-minds/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-12T16:56:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://ardentdeveloper.com/blog/2013/08/12/tympanus-codrops-useful-resources-and-inspiration-for-creative-minds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a HTML/CSS 3 novice, I was searching for resources that could navigate me in the right direction. That is when I stumbled upon <a href="http://tympanus.net/codrops/">Codrops</a>, by Tympanus. At Codrops you can find several articles and tutorials about the latest web trends, techniques and new possibilities. There are 5 categories of content in Codrops. I will you through each of these categories.</p>

<h3>Tutorials</h3>

<p>This section provides you detailed tutorials of how to play with HTML, CSS and Javascript to create innovative products like transition effects, menus, 3D animation etc. Each tutorial is written by an expert and they take all the necessary steps to make sure that the audience understands each and every step. Take a look at a <a href="http://tympanus.net/codrops/2013/07/30/google-nexus-website-menu/">sample tutorial</a>. Each tutorial will have links to the demo website and also the source files required for the tutorial.</p>

<h3>Articles</h3>

<p>This section contains different articles web design, development and related topics. Real web gurus share their thoughts and experience, which is helpful for all levels of web development. There are articles which deal with the best practices can be followed, while designing for the web. Here is a <a href="http://tympanus.net/codrops/2013/01/24/creative-layouts-and-interactions-in-web-design/">sample article</a>.</p>

<h3>Playground</h3>

<p>Here you can find all kinds of really cool experiments, plugins and awesome articles related to web development and programming. This is the right place to go if you want some inspirational ideas for your next web project.</p>

<h3>Blueprints</h3>

<p>Unlike the playground collection, <a href="http://tympanus.net/codrops/category/blueprints/">blueprints</a> offer minimal concepts, which would require further tweaks to be used efficiently. Here is a <a href="http://tympanus.net/codrops/2013/06/06/on-scroll-animated-header/">sample blueprint.</a></p>

<h3>Collective</h3>

<p><a href="http://tympanus.net/codrops/collective/">Collective</a> section mostly consists of links to resources outside of Codrops. These are user submitted and even you can submit links to cool resources if you spot any. Or better you can submit your own resources and be noticed.</p>

<p>So, what are you waiting for? Dive into this awesome world of awesomeness and improve your web designing skills.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
